Olha Dovbnia

Technical Writer

https://chamomi.github.io/TechWritingPortfolio/

PROFILE

Enthusiastic, user-oriented Technical Writer motivated to create clear documentation by bringing excellent writing and communication skills, ML engineering background and user empathy. Offering technical writing experience including the preparation of user guides, tutorials, glossaries, and product overviews for various software product types. Highly motivated to grow as a Technical Writer and striving to deliver helpful user-facing content.

EXPERIENCE

Paragon Software, Remote — Technical Writer

JULY 2021 - JULY 2022

Created user guides, tutorials, and glossary for online marketplace platform; Prepared product overview for real-time filesystem; edited API reference guide for the filesystem;

Experience with Confluence, JIRA, Microsoft Office and style guide application;

Collaborated with project managers, software engineers, support QA engineers, and other technical writers;

Reviewed documents created by another technical writer

Samsung R&D, Warsaw, Poland — *Natural Language Processing Intern (Engineering)*

MAY 2018 - OCTOBER 2019

Worked in Bixby assistant's speech recognition team. Applied machine learning to language modelling as ML engineer; Experience with Python, Git, JIRA, Linux shell, Bash and Jenkins; Collaborated with teams from other European countries, updated documentation of my team's pipeline on Confluence for internal clients; Mentored a new intern

EDUCATION

Warsaw University of Technology, Warsaw, Poland — *Master of Science in Computer Science (AI specialization)*

OCTOBER 2019 - MARCH 2021

Thesis: Automatic Language Identification for Celtic Texts

Oxford Brookes University, Oxford, UK — Erasmus+ exchange

SEPTEMBER 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

Warsaw University of Technology, Warsaw, Poland — Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

OCTOBER 2015 - JUNE 2019

PUBLICATIONS

Automatic Language Identification for Celtic Texts

To be published in Springer Lecture Notes in Computer Science (LNCS)

arXiv preprint: https://arxiv.org/abs/2203.04831

olgadovbnia97@gmail.com

+48 732016180

Warsaw, Poland
(citizen of Ukraine, work permit in Poland)

SKILLS

Technical Writing

Git

JIRA

Confluence

Microsoft Office

WordPress

ISON

Markdown

HTML / CSS

LaTex

Communication

Teamwork

Attention to Detail

Fast Learner

Problem-Solving

Python Bash

Linux Command Line

Machine Learning

SQL

Ienkins

AWARDS

S. Banach grant for Master's degree Erasmus+ exchange grant

LANGUAGES

English (C2; IELTS 8.5 – February 2020)

Russian (native)

Ukrainian (native)

Polish (B2)

French (B1)